Hello Guys, in today's video we are going to talk
about ICICI Pall AMC IPO.
This IPO is going to be open for application from 12th December to 16th December.
So,
in this video we will first talk about this grey
market premium.  From which
we will get some idea of ​​its listing gain.
After that, details of the company's IPO
, what business does the company do?
What is the future of this industry?  We will understand the
financials and fundamentals of the company
in detail.  And what is my opinion going to be
?  Should I apply or not?   We will
talk about this in the last.  So please
watch the full video.  Now first of all if we
talk about grey market premium.
Its current GMP is running around 200 here.  This
means we can
see an estimated listing gain of around 9%.  That
means, if we talk on a per lot basis, then a
profit of up to ₹1200 can be seen.
Approximately.  However, the GMP is
just an estimate.  There is
no guarantee that it will perform like this and
it also keeps changing from time to time.
We have to take care of this thing also.  Now if we
talk about the business of this company, then
this company was started in 1993.
ICICI PDL AMC is an asset management company.  That
is, this is the company that runs mutual funds.  In
which people
try to earn long term returns by investing their money.
Their simple funda is first manage the risk and
then earn returns.  As of September 2025,
its quarterly average asset under
management was Rs 10.1 lakh crore.  Meaning
they have both people's trust and money.
Not only mutual funds, they
also provide PMS i.e. portfolio management services.  Apart from this,
advisory services are also provided for alternative investment funds and offshore investors.  And the
pan India presence is also solid.  273
offices across 27 states and four
union territories.  Let us now quickly
discuss the details of this IPO.  The
price band of this IPO has been
kept at ₹2061 to ₹265 per share.  The total issue
size here is going to be ₹162 crore
and the entire issue is going to be offered for sale here.  The
face value here
is set at ₹1 per share.  Six shares are kept here in one lot.  That
means you will have to pay a
minimum of ₹12,990 to apply for this IPO.
You
can see the timeline of this IPO on the screen here.  This IPO will be listed on 19th December
and you can
apply for this IPO till 5:00 pm on 16th December.
Let us now talk about its financials.  First of all,
if we
look at its assets, the assets
look good to us here.  We are seeing year on year growth
in assets.
In FY25, the company's assets were
around Rs 4383 crore.  Talking about total income or
revenue,
we are seeing year on year growth in this also.  The
company's revenue in FY25 was
around Rs 4979 crore.  Talking about profit after tax, the
company's profit in financial year 23 was
around ₹155 crore.  Which increased to
2549 CR in FY24 and
further increased to around 2650 CR in FY25.
So,
we are seeing continuous year after year growth in profits here.
After that, we can see the abid net worth and reserve
and surplus right here.
And the best part is that the
company is almost debt free here.  Now
if we talk about its fundamentals then the
ROE and ROw of the company are
looking quite good here.  It is much more than 15%, so
this is a good thing.  And if we
talk about its PE ratio i.e. Price to Earnings Ratio, then post IPO it
is going to be around 33.  And
if we compare its PE ratio with its peer group
company, then its PE
ratio is around the industry average here.
So the company is looking good here in terms of PE also.
Let us now come to the conclusion whether one should
apply for this IPO
or not.
Talk from the point of view of listing gains.  The first
point we have to make is its GMP.  The GMP
we saw is running around 9% of this.   That
means some listing gain is expected
here according to GMP.
However, we should not rely entirely on GMP here.
Second, our point
comes here, its anchor list.  So look,
I personally feel that its ankle list
looks quite good here.
Be it FIIs or DIIs,
we are seeing many well-known names in its ankle list.
Our third point
here is its valuation.  So
overall, looking at its financials, its
fundamentals, its PE
ratio, comparing it with its peer group companies,
I personally feel that
its valuation is fine here.  And
fourth our point here comes the
demand for this IPO.  So see, it is a very popular
company.  The issue size is also quite large.   There is a
good demand for this company here.
I personally feel that
we may see a good demand for this IPO.
However, we will know what the actual situation is only
till the last day.
So looking at all the things overall,
personally I am
interested in this IPO for now.
However, you have to take your decision at your own risk and
on your own analysis.  If you are also
applying for IPOs then
remember one important thing.  If you
apply from multiple demat accounts using the same PAN,
your application will be rejected here.
Meaning, if you apply in the
retail category from two different demat accounts of the same PAN card, then
both will be rejected at the time of allotment.  If
you want to increase your chances of IPO allotment, then
a smart way is to open
separate demat accounts in the names of your family members or friends
who have different PAN
numbers.  With this you
can submit multiple applications and the chances of allotment
naturally increase.  You can open this Demat account
with a broker who does
not charge any joining fee or annual maintenance charges
like Grow Dhan or Fyers
who do not charge AMC.  All three are
excellent options.  Each one has its own
unique advantages.  Like Grow Simple
& Trusted Stocks, Mutual Funds,
Gold & IPO all in one place. Dhan Free
Account Zero Delivery Brokerage Fast IPO
by UPI Fires 5 Minute Setup Powerful
Charting Thematic Investment Options
Smart investing starts with the
right demat account Choose wisely Let's see
how the GMPA subscription etc. of ICICI PDL's IPO goes, I also keep
updating it here on Telegram from time to time.
You can join there.
You will find the link in the description of the video.
What do you think about this IPO?  What are you going to
do?  Please share your opinion in the comment section.  That's all for
today's video.  If you
liked the video then like it.
My name is Sunil.  See you
in the next video, thanks for watching.